[
  {
    "_id": "q1",
    "question": "What is an event?",
    "answer": "An event is any interactivity with the user and the DOM such as clicking on an element, typing on an input element, moving the mouse/cursor, etc."
  },
  {
    "_id": "q2",
    "question": "What is the difference between an HTML element event and React event?",
    "note": "Note: Author prefers to use event listeners in javascript rather than directly in HTML as a way to follow \"Separation of Concern\"",
    "answer": "Below are the differences between HTML and React event",
    "list": [
      "Events are written in lowercase in HTML, while camelCase in React",
      "Event handlers are written as string in HTML, while embedded directly inside of brackets {} in React"
    ]
  },
  {
    "_id": "q3",
    "question": "Write at least 4 keyboard events?",
    "answer": "Only 3 keyboard events found in source [1]; one of which is obsolete.",
    "list": [
      "`onKeyDown`",
      "`onKeyUp`",
      "`onKeyPress` obsolete in Javascript"
    ],
    "footnote": [
      "[MDN Source](https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/KeyboardEvent#obsolete_events)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "_id": "q4",
    "question": "Write at least 8 mouse events?",
    "answer": "Below are the mouse events found. Pointer, Wheel, and Drag can be included here since they are derived from Mouse Events",
    "list": [
      "`onClick`",
      "`onContextMenu` (right click)",
      "`onDoubleClick`",
      "`onMouseEnter`",
      "`onMouseLeave` [1]",
      "`onMouseDown`",
      "`onMouseUp`",
      "`onMouseOver`",
      "`onMouseOut` [1]",
      "`onMouseMove`"
    ],
    "footnote": [
      "mouseleave vs mouseout: [MDN Source](https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Element/mouseout_event#mouseout_and_mouseleave)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "_id": "q5",
    "question": "What are the most common mouse and keyboard events?",
    "answer": "The most common events noticed so far are listed below",
    "list": [
      "`onClick`",
      "`onKeyDown`"
    ]
  },
  {
    "_id": "q6",
    "question": "Write an event specific to input element?",
    "answer": "`onInput` and `onChange`"
  },
  {
    "_id": "q7",
    "question": "Write an event specific to form element?",
    "answer": "`onSubmit={ e => e.preventDefault() }`"
  },
  {
    "_id": "q8",
    "question": "Display the coordinate of the view port when a mouse is moving on the body?",
    "answer": "`onMouseMove={ (e) => console.log(e.clientX, e.clientY) }`"
  },
  {
    "_id": "q9",
    "question": "What is the difference between onInput, onChange and onBlur?",
    "answer": "The differences are listed below:",
    "list": [
      "`onInput` triggers on every character keyed in. eg. if you type in 'react' in an input element, it will register: 'r', 're', ... 'react",
      "`onChange` only triggers after desired entry has been keyed in. eg. in the same scenario, what will only register is 'react'",
      "`onBlur` only triggers after the input element has lost focus. Note that onBlur will trigger AFTER onChange in the scenario being used in this section"
    ]
  },
  {
    "_id": "q10",
    "question": "Where do we put the onSubmit event?",
    "answer": "`onSubmit` event is placed in a form element"
  }
]